<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OMS Notes</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on OMS Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 20:20:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/6250/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 20:20:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/6250/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Welcome to Computer Networking We&amp;rsquo;ll be covering advanced concepts in networking such as software defined networking (SDN), data center networking (DCN) and content distribution. You&amp;rsquo;ll complete projects using a state of the art network emulator called mini-net to understand and explore these advanced concepts leading up to a final project replicating actual networking research.
Computer Networking Welcome to the graduate course on computer networking. The primary goal of this course is to provide a survey of the necessary tools, techniques, and concepts to perform research in computer communications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>/7646/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 20:09:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/7646/python/</guid>
      <description>Python: Numpy &amp;amp; Pandas Dataframes A dataframe is a data structure in pandas that allows multiple datasets to be mapped to the same indices. For example, a data frame that maps dates to closing prices could be:
    SPY AAPL GOOG GLD     2000-01-09 101.01 50.89 NaN NaN   2000-01-10 100.05 50.91 NaN NaN   &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip;   2015-12-31 200.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture and Principles</title>
      <link>/6250/architecture-and-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 20:31:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/6250/architecture-and-principles/</guid>
      <description>Architecture &amp;amp; Principles We&amp;rsquo;ll begin our foray into networking by reviewing the history of the internet and its design principles. Networking today is an eclectic mix of theory and practice in large part because the early internet architects set out with clear goals and allowed flexibility in achieving them.
With all that flexibility, does that mean we&amp;rsquo;ll see the rollout of IPv6 soon? Only in your dreams.
A Brief History of the Internet In this lesson we will cover a brief history of the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Analysis of Time Series Data</title>
      <link>/7646/statistical-analysis-of-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 20:09:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/7646/statistical-analysis-of-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>Statistical Analysis of Time Series Data Pandas makes it simple to perform statistical analysis on dataframes, which is extremely important in determining different indicators and acting as inputs to the learning algorithms.
Global statistics For example, if you had a dataframe df1 which had the closing prices for various stocks over a given time period, you can retrieve an ndarray with the mean of the columns by just calling df1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching</title>
      <link>/6250/switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 20:53:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/6250/switching/</guid>
      <description>Switching At its core, a network serves to route packets between machines on the network. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how packets are moved across networks. It&amp;rsquo;s more complicated than it sounds at first, but quite fascinating.
That&amp;rsquo;s right. To even reach your screen, the packets that make up this video likely traveled across at least four or five networks, if not more.
You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how that works in the routing videos on BGP, a routing protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Economics</title>
      <link>/7646/essential-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/7646/essential-economics/</guid>
      <description>Essential Economics This chapter discusses terminology, stock market dynamics, and important indicators in economics. This will allow us to more accurately judge the value of an economic decision and make predictions on the market.
Funds We’ll discuss three different types of funds: Exchange-Traded Fund (ETF), mutual funds, and hedge funds. Different types of funds are governed under different rules. ETFs are similar to stocks in that they are bought and sold at will like stocks- very liquid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routing</title>
      <link>/6250/routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 21:07:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/6250/routing/</guid>
      <description>Routing Overview With your head wrapped around routing we&amp;rsquo;ll now take a look at the nuts and bolts that make routing possible: naming, addressing and forwarding.
And you&amp;rsquo;ll start your first significant Mininet project. In the project you&amp;rsquo;ll investigate switched buffer sizing which can have an important effect on network performance.
Internet Routing The next few lessons will cover internet routing. Contrary to what you might think, the internet is not a single network, but rather a collection of tens of thousands of independently operated networks, or autonomous systems, sometimes simply called ASes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Algorithms</title>
      <link>/7646/machine-learning-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 20:09:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/7646/machine-learning-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Algorithms In most cases, machine learning algorithms are focused on building a model. Then, the model can be used to take inputs and give outputs based on the model. The model is a tool to predict outputs based on the inputs. In our case, we will be using models to take information about stocks and predict their future prices.
So we use machine learning to take historical data and generate a model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naming Addressing and Forwarding</title>
      <link>/6250/naming-addressing-and-forwarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:59:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/6250/naming-addressing-and-forwarding/</guid>
      <description>Naming, Addressing &amp;amp; Forwarding IP Addressing In this lesson we will be covering IP addressing. In particular we will be covering IPv4 address structure and allocation. IP stands for Internet Protocol, and version four is the version of the protocol that is widely deployed on the Internet to date. Each IP address is a 32-bit number. And that 32-bit number is formatted in what is called dotted quad notation. For example, the IP address for http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Router Design</title>
      <link>/6250/router-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 20:21:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/6250/router-design/</guid>
      <description>Router Design In this lesson, we will cover the design of big, fast, modern routers. Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of two modern router chassis. On the left, we have a picture of the Cisco CRS-1, and on the right, we have a picture of the Juniper M320. The M320 has for some time been used at the border of the Georgia Tech network between Georgia Tech and the rest of the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS</title>
      <link>/6250/dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 20:26:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/6250/dns/</guid>
      <description>DNS: Domain Name System Domain Name System Part 1 We&amp;rsquo;ll now have a look at the domain name system or DNS. The purpose of the domain name system is to map human readable names such http://www.gatech.edu to IP addresses such as 130.207.160.173. A name such as this is human readable and much easier to remember and type than an IP address. But in fact, the IP address is what&amp;rsquo;s needed to send traffic to the intended destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congestion Control and Streaming</title>
      <link>/6250/congestion-control-and-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 20:33:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/6250/congestion-control-and-streaming/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 6: Congestion Control, &amp;amp; Streaming In this section of the course we&amp;rsquo;ll learn about resource control and content distribution. Resource control deals with handling bandwidth constraints on links. And in this first section, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on controlling congestion along links. To learn more about TCPA and congestion control, your Mininet project will explore what happens when congestion control goes wrong.
Congestion Control Okay, we&amp;rsquo;re starting course two on congestion control and streaming.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>